QASIM KARIMI

Denver, CO • qasim.almotech@gmail.com • (720) 750-1066 • <u>www.linkedin.com/in/qasim-karimi</u>

Authorized to Work in the United States without Sponsorship

Summary

Skilled, multilingual (English, Persian, and Dari), **Full Stack Web Developer** with expertise building applications, and working with web technologies, programming languages, front-end and back-end tools to design applications and manage databases to increase automation and improve efficiency. Possesses a deep understanding of JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, React.js, PHP, and Laravel among several other languages and tools.

Embraces new technologies and implements best-practice standards to solve complex problems. Possesses a superb grasp of both the technical skills and business acumen necessary to effectively communicate with internal and external clients.

Strengths

- Software Development
- Asynchronous Programming
- System Administration
- Database Creation & Management
- Team Lead | Project Management
- Solutions Consultant
- Code Review | De-Bugging
- Problem Solving

- Takes Initiative
- Detailed | Organized
- Collaborative
- Adaptable

Technical Skills

| Front-End Development | JavaScript, React.js, Angular, Vue.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap |
|------------------------------|--|
| Back-End Development | PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter |
| Microservices and Serverless | API, RESTful API, Docker, Swagger UI, Postman API, JSON |
| Database Management | RDBMS, MySQL, phpMyAdmin |
| UX/ UI Web Design | WordPress, Material Design, Bootstrap |
| Version Control | Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket |
| Project Management | Agile Project Management, Scrum |
| Server Side | Node.js, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cPanel & WHM, Plesk, Webmin |

Career Experience

UPWORK FREELANCE 2021-2023

Full Stack Developer — Remote

- Negotiated contracted project assignments via Up Work, drafted project proposals and presented them to potential partners
- Developed two calculator apps using React.js
- Created an application which senses advertisements, integrating social media platforms, including TikTok, Google Ads, and Facebook and wrote ad scripts for influencers
- Contracted to diagnose, debug, and resolve issues for a website using WordPress
- Created six projects, all rated 5-Stars with 500+ tracked hours achieving an 85% job success rate

...continued...

Qasim Karimi

Page | 2

KABUL CITY MUNICIPALITY 2020-2023

Management Information System (MIS) Specialist — Kabul, Afghanistan

- Led multiple projects using PHP, Laravel, and MySQL (showcased in the project list below)
- Managed and assigned projects to **four** software development staff; guided independent and team projects, including drafting, database design, workflow, testing, and problem-solving
- Received requests and gathered project requirements from city government departments, and managed all documentation, parameters, and reporting for each project
- Oversaw the transition of all government systems from analog to digital, including digitization of city residential data, building project data, property rental/ ownership data, and city tax data
- Trained 40 staff members to implement new application and database

TRUTH LAND COMPANY 2013-2020

IT Manager | Database and Website Developer — Kabul, Afghanistan

- Oversaw software, development, and IT system maintenance for a construction company comprised of 100 staff members
- Developed and maintained the company website using HTML, CSS, WordPress, Bootstrap, jQuery, Apache, while also managing cPanel & WHM webmail
- Created a robust database and application inventory system for stock and asset management, and tracked 3,000 products between four warehouses
- Trained five staff to utilize the inventory database, and created an alert system to notify staff when inventory stock was low
- Maintained and optimized the company's network, managed internet speed and all staff users within the network, and registered Mac addresses for Mac filtering

Education | Coursera Certifications

B.S. in Computer Science | Specialization in Software Engineering | Kabul University, Afghanistan

Building Database Applications in PHP — University of Michigan

Advanced React — Meta

Version Control — Meta

Database Structures and Management with MySQL

Specialization Certificate in Secure Coding with Laravel — INFOSEC

Introduction to Relational Databases (RDBMS) — IBM

Developing Front-End Apps with React — IBM

Application Development Using Microservices and Serverless — IBM

Work Samples

Please see work samples on my website and Gitlab

Personal website: https://gitlab.com/qasim.almotech